Alex Rodriguez - Full Stack Software Developer

New York, NY, 11373 | 347-419-6794 | alexrod102797@gmail.com github.com/alex-png | alex-png.github.io | linkedin.com/in/alexrodriguez97

PROFILE

Fast learning full-stack software engineer driven by desire to understand. Through my background in conference mediation, sales and customer service, I have the ability to swiftly understand, extract and condense the essence of abstract concepts. These skills transitioned into my experience in Ruby on Rails, Javascript and React, making me an ideal candidate for fostering strong relationships and creating apps that generate a personalized experience for users. **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, JQuery, React.is, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Git, HTML5, CSS3, Adobe Photoshop, Web Development.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Find MyBeer - GitHub FrontEnd | GitHub BackEnd | Demo

A personalized beer recommendation system.

- Developed Rails API to parse user data and output recommended beers based on user data and similarity of "interested" beers.
- Successfully averted the issue of inconsistent data by scraping BreweryDB API data to create beer and brewery models with relevant information.
- Implemented user-interface employing React and Redux with pure CSS for styling.

Mobflix - GitHub FrontEnd | GitHub BackEnd | Demo

A Netflix emulation using movie clips from Youtube.

- Constructed Rails API with endpoints for videos and users information.
- Developed user-interface with React and entirely custom CSS.
- Employed long-polling via AJAX to mimic real-time commenting.

NilClass Destroyer - GitHub FrontEnd | Demo

Destroy students of NilClass in this bubble shooter game!

- Collaborated with a team to produce game mechanics through use of Javascript and jQuery.
- Utilized HTML5 to create visual interface for game components.
- Responsible for user interface, creating graphics in Adobe Photoshop.

EXPERIENCE

Moderator & Sales, Legend D'Oro, New York, NY.

05/2018 - Present

- Mediated and condensed abstract ideas from an audience of over 300 potential clients to artist during time-constrained live paintings.
- Surpassed sales goals averaging upwards of \$3,000 each showcase, ensuring equity for future exhibitions.
- Networked on artist's behalf, sparking future collaborations and commissions.

Invited Speaker, Asian Heritage Conference, LaGuardia C.C. Inc., Long Island City, NY.

02/2018 - 04/2018

- Led initiative in overhauling annual recurring theme to a modern, pragmatic discussion question: How can we adapt Buddhist doctrine for the Age of Information?
- Conducted independent research, later collaborating with team to synthesize into group analysis.
- Coordinated weekly meetings to ensure the team covered possible edge cases.
- Presented research and analysis to an audience of over 100 people, furthering discussion beyond research.

Professional Server including Simon & The Whale, Taverna Kyclades. New York, NY.

12/2014 - 08/2019

- Exceeded sales goals through suggestive tactics and upselling products strategies.
- Fostered distinct culture in workplace among colleagues and clients, producing recurring patrons.
- Memorized and maintained intricate knowledge on rotating wine and food selections as to tailor client.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

08/2019 -12/2019

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React.js program

City University of New York, LaGuardia Community College. Long Island City, NY.

Associate of Arts in Communications and Public Relations

03/2017 - 12/2018

• Effigy of The Forgotten, science-fiction short story published in **Literary LaGuardia**. Won second place in Creative Writing Contest. Presented to over 200 students and professors in the Literary Laguardia Launch Party.